Guide to the John Guare Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John Guare papers
1914-2010
YCAL MSS 411
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
111.23
(132 boxes)
The John Guare Papers document the work and life of the playwright and educator John Guare. The papers consist of production files, professional correspondence, writings, writings of others, subject files, personal effects, personal papers, photographs, printed material, and one reel-to-reel sound recording. The bulk of the material spans the years 1962-2010.
Guare, John, 1938-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from George Robert Minkoff Inc. on the Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection Fund and the Edwin J. Beinecke Fund, 1995.
July 2012 Acquisition: Purchased from George Robert Minkoff Inc. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, the Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection Fund, the Bradford F. and Lila L. Swan Fund, and various other funds, 2012. For more information consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 58 (financial papers): Restricted until January 1, 2085. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Boxes 131, 133 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 64, 130 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copy may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Printed material received with the collection was removed for separate cataloging and can be accessed by searching the library's online catalog.
John Guare
John Guare, American playwright, was born in New York City on February 5, 1938 and raised in Jackson Heights, Queens. He was interested in theatre from a young age, writing his first play, "Universe," at age eleven. He received his Bachelor of Arts from Georgetown University (1960) and his Master of Fine Arts from Yale School of Drama (1963). His early works were well-received comic one-act plays, including To Wally Pantoni, We Leave a Credenza (1964), Cop-Out (1968) and Muzzeha (1968). He received an Obie Award for Muzzeha but did not gain national attention until 1971, with his first full-length play, The House of the Blue Leaves. The play received an Obie Award and New York Drama Critics Circle Award for Best American Play. The same year, Two Gentlemen of Verona, won a Tony Award, a Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Lyrics (he shared this with co-writer Mel Shapiro), and in 1972 won the New York Drama Critics Circle Award for Best Musical. With these two plays, Guare became known as a leading American dramatist.
Guare's plays are characterized as highly theatrical, exploring the bizarre and comic sides of human relationships and desires. Their settings are varied, including several based in nineteenth-century America. He has also been involved in musical theatre. Since his initial success in 1971, Guare has worked steadily and successfully.
The 1986 Broadway revival of The House of Blue Leaves won Guare four Tony Awards. His Six Degrees of Separation (1990) won an Obie Award, the New York Drama Critics Circle Award, London's Olivier Award for Best Play, and was a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize in Drama. It was turned into a film in 1993. Two Gentlemen of Verona was revived in 2005 at the Public Theater's Shakespeare in the Park and Guare won (again sharing with Mel Shapiro) the Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Book of a Musical.
Guare's other plays include Rich and Famous (1974); Landscape of the Body, for which he also wrote the songs (1977); Marco Polo Sings a Solo (1977); Bosoms and Neglect (1979); Lydie Breeze (1982); Gardenia (1982); The Race to Urga (1986); Women and Water (1990); Four Baboons Adoring the Sun (1992); Lake Hollywood (1999); Chaucer in Rome, sequel to The House of Blue Leaves (2001); and A Few Stout Individuals (2002). He also wrote the screenplay for Louis Malle's film Atlantic City (1980), for which he was nominated for an Oscar.
In addition to his work as a playwright, Guare is an influential leader in other areas of theatre. He was a founding member in 1965 of the Eugene O'Neill Theatre Center in Waterford, Connecticut and was a Resident Playwright at the New York Shakespeare Festival in 1976. He currently teaches at the Yale School of Drama, co-produces the New Plays Reading Room Series at the Lincoln Center Library for the Performing Arts, is a council member of the Dramatists Guild, and a co-editor of the Lincoln Center Theater Review. Other awards include the Award of Merit from the American Academy of Arts and Letters and the PEN/Laura Pels Foundation Awards for Drama.
Scope and Contents
The John Guare Papers document the work and life of the playwright John Guare. The papers consist of production files, professional correspondence, writings, writings of others, subject files, personal effects, personal papers, photographs, printed material, computer disks, and one sound recording, spanning the years 1914-2010.
The bulk of the collection consists of production files for the many stage and screenplays authored by Guare. These production files include draft scripts, correspondence, and publicity materials. The papers shed light on his creative process and the stage production of his works.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Professional Papers, 1962-1995. II. Works of Others, 1914-1982. III. Personal Papers, 1971-1989. IV. Printed Material, 1960-1995. V. July 2012 Acquisition, 1900s-2010.
Dramatists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; American drama -- 20th Century; Theater -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Photographic prints; Theater scripts; Theater programs; Sound recordings; Dramatists; Guare, John, 1938-
- Professional Papers, 1962-1995; Series I; 52.42; (53 boxes)
  Arrangement
  This series is organized into two subseries: Production Files and Professional Correspondence and Subject Files.
  Scope and Contents
  Professional Papers contains scripts, drafts, notes, correspondence, research files, publicity files, computer disks, and other materials related to the production of stage and screen plays written by Guare, as well as materials relating to other aspects of his professional career.
  - Production Files, 1962-1995
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by production title.
    - Atlantic City, 1979-1995; 22 (Box 1)
    - Atlantic City (continued), 1979-1981; 18 (Box 2)
    - Bamboozle, 1979; 5 (Box 2)
    - Big Kiss, 1982; 24 (Box 3)
    - Big Kiss (continued), 1982-1986; 14 (Box 4)
    - Bluebeard, undated; 2 (Box 4)
    - Bosoms and Neglect, circa 1978-1993; 5 (Box 4)
    - Bosoms and Neglect (continued), circa 1978-1993; 19 (Box 5)
    - Bosoms and Neglect (continued), circa 1978-1993; 24 (Box 6)
    - Bosoms and Neglect (continued), circa 1978-1993; 6 (Box 7)
    - Carlock, undated (Box 7)
    - Cop-Out, undated; 12 (Box 7)
    - "A Day for Surprises", undated (Box 7)
    - The Exception and the Rule, undated; 4 (Box 7)
    - Eye Contact, undated; 4 (Box 7)
    - Eye Contact (continued), 1985-1987; 17 (Box 8)
    - Eye Contact (continued), 1985-1987; 19 (Box 9)
    - Faustus in Hell, 1985 (Box 10)
    - 500 Dancers Fall Out of the Sky, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
    - Floy-Floy, 1979; 3 (Box 10)
    - Found Money, undated; 2 (Box 10)
    - Four Baboons Adoring the Sun, 1991-1993; 15 (Box 10)
    - Four Baboons Adoring the Sun (continued), 1991-1993; 23 (Box 11)
    - Gardenia, 1981-1987; 23 (Box 12)
    - Gardenia (continued), 1981-1983; 13 (Box 13)
    - The Golden Cherub, 1962 (Box 13)
    - The Great Asker, undated (Box 13)
    - Hey, Stay Awhile, 1984; 4 (Box 13)
    - Holiday for Henrietta, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Home Fires, 1969; 7 (Box 13)
    - Hoodwink, 1979; 3 (Box 13)
    - The House of Blue Leaves, 1967-1986; 19 (Box 14)
    - The House of Blue Leaves (continued), 1967-1986; 10 (Box 15)
    - How About You?, 1980; 2 (Box 15)
    - I Hate My Life, 1988; 7 (Box 15)
    - Ibsen Preface, 1978 (Box 15)
    - In Fireworks Lie Secret Codes, 1978-1980; 12 (Box 15)
    - Landscape of the Body, 1977-1994; 21 (Box 16)
    - Landscape of the Body (continued), 1977-1994; 26 (Box 17)
    - Last Night, 1980; 9 (Box 18)
    - The Loveliest Afternoon of the Year, 1966-1992; 4 (Box 18)
    - Lydie Breeze, circa 1978-1986; 12 (Box 18)
    - Lydie Breeze (continued), circa 1978-1986; 27 (Box 19)
    - Lydie Breeze (continued), circa 1978-1986; 21 (Box 20)
    - Lydie Breeze (continued), circa 1978-1986; 26 (Box 21)
    - Lydie Breeze (continued), circa 1978-1986; 31 (Box 22)
    - Lydie Breeze (continued), circa 1978-1986; 27 (Box 23)
    - Lydie Breeze (continued), circa 1978-1986; 28 (Box 24)
    - Lydie Breeze (continued), circa 1978-1986; 27 (Box 25)
    - Lyrics, undated; 2 (Box 25)
    - Manna from Heaven, 1992; 2 (Box 26)
    - Marco Polo Sings a Solo, circa 1976-1977; 19 (Box 26)
    - Marco Polo Sings a Solo (continued), circa 1976-1977; 20 (Box 27)
    - Marco Polo Sings a Solo (continued), circa 1976-1977; 11 (Box 28)
    - Moon Over Miami, circa 1981-1992; 14 (Box 28)
      Separated Materials
      Eleven 5-1/4-inch computer disks stored separately as Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Moon Over Miami (continued), circa 1981-1992; 19 (Box 29)
    - Moon Over Miami (continued), circa 1981-1992; 15 (Box 30)
    - Moon Over Miami (continued), circa 1981-1992; 17 (Box 31)
    - Moon Under Miami, 1994-1995; 3 (Box 31)
    - Moon Under Miami (continued), 1994-1995; 6 (Box 32)
    - Muzeeka, 1994; 6 (Box 32)
    - N. Y. C. I. A., 1978-1979; 9 (Box 32)
    - N. Y. I. H., undated (Box 32)
    - A New Me, 1978; 3 (Box 33)
    - New York Actor, circa 1988-1994; 25 (Box 33)
    - New York Actor (continued), circa 1988-1994; 2 (Box 34)
    - Oh Kay, 1977; 2 (Box 34)
    - Only Children, undated; 3 (Box 34)
    - Orchards, 1985 (Box 34)
    - Pledge of Allegiance, 1979-1981; 6 (Box 34)
    - Pursuit of Happiness, 1980 (Box 34)
    - Razzle Dazzle, 1978 (Box 34)
    - Rich and Famous, circa 1979; 7 (Box 34)
    - Rich and Famous (continued), circa 1979; 17 (Box 35)
    - Sicilian Visions, undated; 3 (Box 35)
    - Six Degrees of Separation, circa 1986-1993; 20 (Box 36)
    - Six Degrees of Separation (continued), circa 1986-1993; 15 (Box 37)
    - Six Degrees of Separation (continued), circa 1986-1993; 25 (Box 38)
    - Six Degrees of Separation (continued), circa 1986-1993; 15 (Box 39)
    - Six Degrees of Separation (continued), circa 1986-1993; 28 (Box 40)
    - Six Degrees of Separation (continued), circa 1986-1993; 32 (Box 41)
    - Sophisticated Ladies, 1981 (Box 42)
    - Take a Dream, 1978; 7 (Box 42)
    - Theatre Accident '47, 1984 (Box 42)
    - Three Exposures: The House of Blue Leaves, Landscape of the Body, and Bosoms and Neglect, 1982; 6 (Box 42)
    - To Wally Pantoni, We Leave a Credenza, 1965; 5 (Box 42)
    - The Toadstool Boy and the 30s Girl, 1960 (Box 42)
    - 20,000 Zombies, 1985; 2 (Box 42)
    - 20,000 Zombies (continued), 1985; 15 (Box 43)
    - Two Gentlemen of Verona, 1972-1975; 18 (Box 44)
    - Twyla, undated; 6 (Box 44)
    - Women and Water, circa 1984-1987; 16 (Box 44)
    - Women and Water (continued), circa 1984-1987; 22 (Box 45)
    - Women and Water (continued), circa 1984-1987; 22 (Box 46)
    - Women and Water (continued), circa 1984-1987; 16 (Box 47)
    - Women and Water (continued), circa 1984-1987; 15 (Box 48)
    - Women and Water (continued), circa 1984-1987; 18 (Box 49)
    - Unidentified writings and notes, undated; 11 (Box 50)
  - Professional Correspondence and Subject Files, circa 1977-1995
    This subseries is arranged in the order in which it was received.
    - General correspondence, arranged alphabetically, circa 1977-1982; 27 (Box 51)
    - Professional correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1983-1994; 16 (Box 52)
    - Subject Files, including correspondence, 1983-1995; 19 (Box 53)
      Includes files on the American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, Harvard University, Juilliard School, New York Institute for Arts and Humanities, the Lincoln Center New Theater Review, and the Dramatists Guild Barr Deposition of John Guare, as well as assorted other professional correspondence.
- Works of Others, 1914-1982; Series II; 3; (3 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by author. Works by unidentified creators is filed at the end of the series.
  Works of Others contains copies of scripts, drawings, and other works by others.
  - Albee, Edward. Seascape, 1974 (Box 54)
  - Best, Eva. An American Princess, undated (Box 54)
  - Brustein, Robert. "Welcoming Address", 1978 (Box 54)
  - Cain, Susan. And She Does Windows!, 1981 (Box 54)
  - Carter, Randolph. The Europeans, undated; 3 (Box 54)
  - Chekov, Anton. The Cherry Orchard, 1976 (Box 54)
  - d'Amico, Suso Cacchi. Mortadella, 1971 (Box 54)
  - de la Vergne, Susan. The Woman in Question, undated; 3 (Box 54)
  - Ely, John Hart. Line of Succession, undated (Box 54)
  - Freidman. A Midsummer Night's Dream: a musical version, undated (Box 54)
  - Furch-Allers, Janne. "The Price of Freedom", undated (Box 54)
  - Furth, George. A Husband, A Wife and a Friend, undated (Box 54)
  - Gehm, John. They Came To Bother Us, 1979 (Box 54)
  - Gershwin, Ira. Oh, Kay!, undated; 2 (Box 54)
  - Grady, Annie V. The Garrison Girl, undated (Box 54)
  - Grady, Jere. Pawn Ticket 210, undated (Box 54)
  - Greenleaf, Tony. "Playwriting", 1978 (Box 54)
  - Heilpern, John. The Man Who Almost Knew Johnny Carson, undated (Box 54)
  - Hitchcock, J. S. Bhutan, 1982 (Box 54)
  - Holmes, Jake. Dan John's Final National Tour, 1980 (Box 54)
  - Holzman, Michael, undated; 5 (Box 55)
  - Horowitz, C. James, undated (Box 55)
  - Jacker, Corrine. The Island, undated (Box 55)
  - Kaufman, George S., undated; 2 (Box 55)
  - Kelleher, Ann, undated; 2 (Box 55)
  - Kilmer, Nicholas. Monsieur de Paris, undated (Box 55)
  - Klavan, Lawrence. Scat, 1982 (Box 55)
  - Lerner, Alan Jay. The Little Prince, 1972; 4 (Box 55)
  - MacDermot, Galt. Hair, undated (Box 55)
  - McMillan, D. From Krapp to Footfalls - Dramatic Structure and Technical Controls, undated (Box 55)
  - Matthews, Peter, undated (Box 55)
  - Moshereece, Hilary. Night Babies, 1982 (Box 55)
  - Nixon, Cynthia. "Syphillis", circa 1972 (Box 55)
  - O'Brien, Howard. Split Rock, undated (Box 55)
  - Ordway, Sally. FREE!, 1965 (Box 55)
  - Ordway, Sally. The Life and Opinions of Fanny Trollope, 1981 (Box 55)
  - Ordway, Sally. A Pretty Passion, 1981 (Box 55)
  - Osborne, John. The End of Me Old Cigar, 1974 (Box 55)
  - Pinter, Harold. A la recherche du temps perdu, undated; 3 (Box 55)
  - Pinter, Harold. Betrayal, 1978; 4 (Box 55)
  - Porter, Priscilla. "Some Dead Language", 1980 (Box 55)
  - Rabinowitz, Robert and Nancy Lloyd. Humboldt's Gift, undated (Box 56)
  - Ream, Sarah, undated (Box 56)
  - Reid, Kate. "A Guare", 1979 (Box 56)
  - Rimer, Tom and Leslie Bricusse. Kings and Clowns, 1977 (Box 56)
  - Ritter, Erika. Automatic Pilot, undated (Box 56)
  - Rosener, George M. The Widow's Might, 1914 (Box 56)
  - Ryan, Cate. Birds of North America, 1978 (Box 56)
  - Schwartz, Arthur. "Where Do I Go From You?", undated (Box 56)
  - Shapiro, Mel. Anthony and Inez, undated (Box 56)
  - Shawn, Wallace. Three Short Plays, 1975 (Box 56)
  - Simckes, Seymour. Anathema Maranatha, undated (Box 56)
  - Thompson, Danielle. Picasso, a Musical, undated (Box 56)
  - Vogel, Paula. The Oldest Profession, undated (Box 56)
  - Weller, Michael. Dwarfman, undated (Box 56)
  - Williams, Heathcoate. AC/DC, undated (Box 56)
  - Williams, Tennessee, 1979-1981; 5 (Box 56)
  - Williamson, Anne. Five Big Jacks, 1981 (Box 56)
  - Wulp, John. The Saintliness of Margery Kempe, undated; 3 (Box 56)
  - Zagoren, Marc Alan Princess Grace and the Fazzaris, 1978 (Box 56)
  - Unidentified authors, undated; 6 (Box 56)
- Personal Papers, 1971-1989; Series III; 1.42; (2 boxes)
  This series is arranged by material type.
  Personal Papers contains diaries, appointment books, telephone notebooks, photographs, personal effects, and financial papers.
  - Diaries, appointment books, notebooks, and holograph notes, 1971-1989; 9 (Box 57)
  - Photographs and slides, undated; 5 (Box 57)
  - Drawing, "Tammy Miller circa 1965-3-4"
  - Unidentified 1/4" reel to reel audiotape, undated
    Conditions Governing Access
    Stored in restricted fragile.
  - Personal effects, undated (Box 57)
    Hair pin and broach
  - Financial papers, circa 1975-1985; 13 (Box 58)
    Restricted until January 1, 2085. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
- Printed Material, circa 1960-1995; Series IV; 3; (3 boxes)
  This series is arranged generally by material type and is mostly unsorted.
  This series contains printed materials collected and used by John Guare, including books, pamphlets, magazines, newspapers and newspaper clippings, as well as other ephemera.
  - Newspaper clippings, circa 1960-1995; 24 (Box 59)
  - Other printed materials, circa 1960-1995; 29 (Box 60)
  - Other printed materials, circa 1960-1995; 19 (Box 61)
- Oversize Material, 0.25; (2 boxes)
  - "A Day for Surprises" (Series I), undated (Box 62)
  - House of Blue Leaves (Series I), undated (Box 62)
  - Lydie Breeze (Series I), undated (Box 62)
  - Three Exposures (Series I), undated (Box 63)
  - Two Gentlemen of Verona (Series I), circa 1972-1975 (Box 132)
  - Women and Water (Series I), undated (Box 62)
  - Photographs (Series III), undated (Box 62)
  - Drawing, "Tammy Miller circa 1965-3-4" (Series III) (Box 62)
  - Printed material (Series IV), undated (Box 62)
- Computer and audiovisual media, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copy may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Computer media
    - Moon Over Miami #1, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0001; 1 (Box 133)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Moon Over Miami #2, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0002; 1 (Box 133)
    - moon 3, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0003; 1 (Box 133)
    - WordStar 2 Moon Over Miami #4, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0004; 1 (Box 133)
    - moon #5, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0005; 1 (Box 133)
    - Moon Over Miami #6, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0006; 1 (Box 133)
    - moon #7, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0007; 1 (Box 133)
    - CPM SYSTEM, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0008; 1 (Box 133)
    - moon Six backup, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0009; 1 (Box 133)
    - wordstar, 1995-ycal-0703-m-0010; 1 (Box 133)
    - [no label information], 1995-ycal-0703-m-0011; 1 (Box 133)
  - Untitled, undated; 1; 01:42:27; The program is distorted at times. (Box 64, Item barcode 39002091396961)
    This recording is of a stage performance.
- July 2012 Acquisition, 1900s-2010; Series V
  This portion of the collection is organized into six series: I. Correspondence. II. Professional Papers. III. Works of Others. IV. Personal Papers. V. Printed Material. VI. Audiovisual Material.
  - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 65)
  - Professional Papers, 1980s-2000s
    Organized into rough groupings by work and arranged alphabetically by title.
    Contains scripts, drafts, notes, correspondence, research files, publicity files, and other materials related to the production of stage and screen plays written by Guare, as well as materials relating to other aspects of his professional career.
    - Brigadoon, 2000s (Box 66)
    - Chaucer in Rome, 2000s (Box 67)
    - Chaucer in Rome, 2000s (Box 68)
    - Chaucer in Rome, 2000s (Box 69)
    - Dietrich & Marlene, 1992-1994 (Box 70)
    - Dietrich & Marlene, 1994 (Box 71)
    - The Exception and the Rule, 1980s (Box 72)
    - The Exception and the Rule and Race Through the Desert, 1970s-1980s (Box 73)
    - The Exception and the Rule, 2000s (Box 74)
    - A Few Stout Individuals, 1990s (Box 75)
    - A Few Stout Individuals, 1990s (Box 76)
    - A Few Stout Individuals, 1990s-2000s (Box 77)
    - A Few Stout Individuals, 1990s-2000s (Box 78)
    - A Few Stout Individuals, 1990s-2000s (Box 79)
    - Free Man of Color, 2000s (Box 80)
    - Free Man of Color, 2000s (Box 81)
    - Free Man of Color, 2000s (Box 82)
    - Free Man of Color, 2000s (Box 83)
    - Free Man of Color, 2000s-2010s (Box 84)
    - Free Man of Color, 2006 (Box 85)
    - Free Man of Color, 2006-2007 (Box 86)
    - Free Man of Color, 2000s-2010s (Box 87)
    - Gerald and Sara, 2000s (Box 88)
    - His Girl Friday, 1930s, 2000s (Box 89)
    - His Girl Friday, 2000s (Box 90)
    - His Girl Friday, 2000s (Box 91)
    - JCW (Joseph Conrad's Wife?) material including clippings and printed material, 1990s-2000s (Box 92)
    - Kiss Me Kate, 1998-1999 (Box 93)
    - Lake Hollywood, 1990s-2000s (Box 94)
    - Lydie Breeze, Bulfinch Mythology, Gardenia, and Women and Water, 1980s-2000s (Box 95)
    - Lydie Breeze, Bulfinch Mythology, Gardenia, and Women and Water, 1980s-2000s (Box 96)
    - Lydie Breeze and Women and Water, 1980s-2000s (Box 97 (Oversize))
    - Marvin's Room, 1990s (Box 98)
    - Marvin's Room, 1990s (Box 99)
    - Mine, 1990s (Box 100)
    - Mine, 1990s (Box 101)
    - Moon Over Miami, 1990s (Box 102)
    - Moon Over Miami, 1990s (Box 103 (Oversize))
    - Rich and Famous, 2000s (Box 104)
    - Six Degrees of Separation, 1980s-2000s (Box 105)
    - Six Degrees of Separation, 1980s-2000s (Box 106)
    - Stark Truth, 1980s-1990s (Box 107)
    - Stark Truth, 1980s-1990s (Box 108)
    - The Sweet Smell of Success, 1990s-2000s (Box 109)
    - The Sweet Smell of Success, 1990s-2000s (Box 110)
    - The Sweet Smell of Success, 1999-2002 (Box 111)
    - The Sweet Smell of Success, 1999-2002 (Box 112)
    - Various works, including 20,000 Zombies; Eye Contact; various manuscripts, typescripts, notes etc., 1990s (Box 113)
    - Various works, including Babes in Arms, A Few Stout Individuals, and others, as well as various personal papers, 1960s-2000s (Box 114)
    - Various works, including Babes in Arms, Kiss Me Kate, Landscape of the Body, Love's Fire, and War Against the Kitchen Sink, 1980s-2000s (Box 115)
    - Various works, including Big Kiss, Landsape of a Body, 20,000 Zombies, and others, 1980s-2000s (Box 116)
    - Various works, including Caminol, Kill An Hour with Ends, Everybody Gets 'It' in the End, Did You Write My Name in the Snow, and others, 1960s-1980s (Box 117)
    - Various works, including Le Million, Atlantic City, House of Blue Leaves, His Girl Friday, Bulfinch's Mythology, Lydie Breeze, Gardenia, and Women and Water, 1960s-2000s (Box 118)
    - Various works, including Lydie Breeze, Lake Hollywood, Lilly of Saint Lawrence, and Mine, 1990s-2000s (Box 119)
    - Various works, including Reading Room Readings, Subway Stories, Sweat Smell of Success, Landscape of the Body, Art as a Political Force, A Chekhov Evening, Two Gentlemen of Verona, and Kiss Me Kate, 1990s (Box 120)
  - Works of Others, 1900s-1940s (Box 121)
    Manuscripts, typescripts, printed materials, clippings, and photographs related to plays by Guare's great uncles Jere Grady and James Grady
  - Personal Papers, 1970s-2000s
    - Diaries ("John's Journals"), 1970s-2000s (Box 122)
    - Watches and wallets, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 123)
  - Printed Material, 1970s-2000s
    Consists of clippings, newspapers, maagazines, and other printed materials, most of which mention or otherwise relate to Guare's work.
    - Clippings, newspapers and magazines, 1970s-2000s (Box 124)
    - Clippings, newspapers and magazines, 1970s-2000s (Box 125 (Oversize))
    - Clippings, newspapers and magazines, 1970s-2000s (Box 126 (Oversize))
    - Magazines and newspapers, 1970s-2000s (Box 127)
    - Magazines and newspapers, 1970s-2000s (Box 128 (Oversize))
    - Magazines and newspapers, 1970s-2000s (Box 129 (Oversize))
  - Audiovisual Material, (8 cassettes and 1 compact disc) (Box 130)